axis.com 2014-02-09

# Axis Communications - Privacy policy

Axis Communications AB (“Axis”) and its subsidiaries are committed to protecting your online privacy. We have designed our web sites in a way that will enable you to visit and access most of the available information and material without having to submit any personal data unless you choose to. However, in order to take part in some of the functions and activities and to get access to some of Axis’ services, it will be necessary for you to provide personal data on certain areas of the web sites. 

By accessing or using an Axis web site, online service or application, you agree to the collection, use and transfer of personal data according to the terms of this Axis online privacy policy. We are posting Axis’ privacy policy online to clearly explain our intentions and create a sound basis for a mutual relationship. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not access or use Axis’ web sites. Axis reserves the right to change the online privacy policy from time to time at its sole discretion. Your use of the web sites will be subject to the most current version of the online privacy policy, published at the time of such use. 

The Axis web sites are published and maintained by Axis Communications AB, with its principal place of business at Emdalavägen 14, SE-223 69 Lund, Sweden. 

## Purpose

Personally identifiable information (“Personal Data”) is data that can be used to uniquely identify or contact a single person. Personal Data that you choose to submit to us or which is collected by us is used solely for the purpose of improving the relations between you and Axis. Axis and its subsidiaries may share this Personal Data with each other and use it consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

## What we collect and why

We collect Personal Data mostly about what interests you on our web sites. We log pages accessed by you in order to improve and develop, and enhance the usability of our web sites. If you register your products, download software or software updates, subscribe to our e-newsletters, register for a web-based course provided by Axis or participate in an online survey we will require or collect more detailed information, including your name, e-mail address, the products purchased by you, contact preferences and credit card information. Sometimes we use a technology involving “cookies”, which enables the web sites to store certain user information on your computer in order for us to customize your experience when accessing the sites. You can read more about how we use cookies below. 

Any Personal Data provided by you and/or collected by us will be handled by us in an appropriate and considerate manner. We will only use your Personal Data to support our mutual relationship, to understand your needs and to improve our support for your needs. Our use of your Personal Data improves our offers and services to you, for instance, by helping you stay informed of new software versions. 

Axis will destroy or de-identify Personal Data submitted by you after a reasonable period of time. Please note however that credit card numbers that you enter are never saved. They are only retained during the transaction and validation process. This may be done using a third party clearing house. 

## Market contact

On occasion we may contact you to provide you with market information that we believe is of interest to you, or we may ask for your opinions in a market survey. We may also notify you of your ability to subscribe to a number of e-newsletters that provide, for example, up-to-date information on our current products or solutions. You will always have the option of telling us whether or not you want to receive such market information or be involved in our research activities. 

## Transfer of Personal Data

Axis will not sell, trade or lease to third parties your Personal Data. Unless we have informed you otherwise and have obtained your permission, or the law forces us to, we will only use the collected Personal Data within Axis or with business partners that act on our behalf. 

As stated previously, you have the option of letting us know if you do not wish to receive unsolicited direct marketing materials, and we will strive to honor your request. 

## Information integrity

Axis strives to keep your Personal Data correct. We will make reasonable efforts to have your Personal Data available to you for viewing, or for making corrections or additions. To protect your Personal Data, we use a personal security login system to verify your identity before allowing you access to your Personal Data. Furthermore, we employ physical and electronic protection mechanisms to secure access and to protect your Personal Data from unauthorized access. 

## Links to other sites

Sometimes you will find links to third party sites on our web sites. Please note that this online privacy policy does not automatically apply to these third party sites. 

## Cookies

As stated above, a “cookie” is a piece of text that enables the web sites to store certain user information on your computer in order for us to customize your experience when accessing the sites. Cookies are used by us in order to analyze your visiting patterns on our web sites and allow us to better match your preferences and facilitate your use of the services provided on an Axis web site. Cookies help us to support customer relations by enabling us, for instance, to simplify your login procedure when you want to download software upgrades. Sometimes we use cookies to make your browsing experience easier or to enable us to make web site usage analysis on an aggregated level (i.e. on a non-personal, collective manner for the purpose of tracking overall movements and visits to certain pages on our web site, for example). By visiting an Axis web site you allow the site to store cookies from Axis and third party companies acting on our behalf on your computer. Please note that most browsers enable you to delete cookies stored on your computer hard drive, block the acceptance of cookies or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. To learn more about these functions, we refer you to your browser instructions. However, if you block acceptance of cookies, we may not be able to restore your preferences and customization settings, and our ability to personalize your online experience will be limited. 

## Contact information

If you have any questions regarding Personal Data held by us or this online privacy policy, please contact us.
